# **Heather Sorrells**

307-258-3507 | Sherrills Ford, NC

LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:https://www.linkedin.com/in/heather-sorrells/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/heather-sorrells/</a>
Email: <a href="mailto:hlsorrells.dev@gmail.com">hlsorrells.dev@gmail.com</a>
Portfolio: <a href="mailto:https://hlsorrells.github.io/">https://hlsorrells.github.io/</a>

Full-stack developer leveraging an accounting background in various industries and a passion for the flow and security of data. My work experience combined with my education and technical training provide me with a unique perspective and approach to business solutions. Known as a dedicated and persistent problem-solver with a desire to leave a legacy of better organization and efficiency, I am driven to learn new technologies across the stack that can keep data secure and prevent fraud.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Git, Python, R, SAS, XML

Frontend: HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, Middleware: Node, Express, Handlebars, Sequelize Backend: SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Pentaho, APIs

## **PROJECTS**

# School Spot | https://bit.ly/RepoSchoolSpot | https://bit.ly/SchoolSpot

Backend

- This project allows teachers and students to track assignments and grades.
- Project is built dynamically using JavaScript, Express.js, Handlebars.js, and MySQL.
- Responsible for creating complex gueries using MySQL and Sequelize.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Express, Handlebars, Sequelize, MySQL.

# **Drinking Bad** | https://bit.ly/RepoDrinkBad | https://bit.ly/DrinkinBad

Backend

- User can request a random drink selection or a Breaking Bad character mashup
- This project is built dynamically in JavaScript leveraging loops, objects and arrays.
- Responsible for making HTML dynamic, pull API data, and constructing the README.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Semantic UI, Breaking Bad API, and CocktailDB.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Laughing Out Loud**

Jan 2017 - Aug 2017

Bookkeeping Assistant - PT

Casper, WY

- Company is a parent corporation for truck stop plaza, two restaurants, a bar, and a hotel.
- Hired for daily cash deposits and A/P for one restaurant, but promoted to handling all A/P and to assist prepping payroll within three months.
- Improved efficiency & organization by updating all filing systems and paperwork flow.
- Assigned special projects such as becoming a ProctorU proctor to certify restaurant personnel and learning how to program a label maker with Excel import to train deli personnel and general manager on usage and operation.

# **Hilltop National Bank**

Mar 2015 - Jan 2017

Trust Operations Clerk

Casper, WY

- Updated the official employee handbook for Trust Operations Trading Desk and created a detailed Trading Desk How-To manual with procedures, protocols, and graphics.
- Hired as the primary trader for money market accounts and trained as backup trader for mutual fund accounts within 4 months.
- Reduced the backlog of document scanning from one year down to one week within 6 months once assigned.

Foss Motors Jul 2010 - Sep 2014

Office Manager Casper, WY

- Promoted to office manager within the first year which allowed me to implement employee cross-training and development of position duty handbooks.
- Hired as "Cashier" and promoted to "In-House Financing Accounts Manager" within 3 months.
- Reconciled over 200 in-house financing accounts to establish a reconcilable ledger for active accounts.
- Reduced completion time of end-of-month duties from 10 days to 3 days.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of North Carolina-Charlotte, Charlotte, NC	Present	
Certificate, Full-Stack Software Development		
Colorado State University-Global, Aurora, CO	May 2020	
Bachelor of Science Degree, Management of Information Systems and Business Analytics		
Graduated with honors, Summa Cum Laude	GPA 4.0	
Casper College, Casper, WY	Jul 2018	
Associate of Applied Science Degree, Economics		
Graduated with honors	GPA 4.0	

## **AWARDS & HONORS**

Statistics and Data Mining for Business Intelligence	Mar 2020
Issued by SAS Institute Inc & Colorado State University-Global	
Delta Mu Delta International Honor Society Member	Apr 2019
IMA Accounting Honor Society Member	Apr 2019
Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society Member	Jan 2015
Sigma Beta Delta International Honor Society Inductee	Feb 2020
Golden Key International Honor Society Inductee	Feb 2020

### PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

IEEE - Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Student Member

AITP - Association of Information Technology Professionals Student Member

ACFE - Association of Certified Fraud Examiners Student Member

IMA - Institute of Management Accountants Student Member

AICPA - American Institute of Certified Public Accountants Student Member